newhaven.edu 2017-06-02

# Online Privacy Statement - University of New Haven

The University of New Haven respects the privacy of all website visitors to the extent permitted by law. This online privacy statement is intended to inform you how this website collects information, how that information may be used, how we protect any information you choose to provide us.

 **There are four types of information that this site may collect during your visit:**

  * network traffic logs
  * website traffic logs
  * cookies
  * voluntary information

**Network Traffic**  
In order to provide network security and the highest possible level of service for all our network users, the University utilizes software and hardware to monitor network traffic, identify and log unauthorized access or access to nonpublic information, detect computer viruses and malware which could damage or disrupt University computers or the network, and monitor and adjust the performance of the University network. This monitoring may include collecting such information as email headers, addresses from network packets, and other data which may or may not have identifying properties. Information from these activities is used only for the purpose of maintaining the security and performance of the University's networks and computer systems. Personally identifiable information from these activities is not released to external parties without your consent unless required by law. 

**Website Traffic**  
University Web sites collect and store information from online visitors to help manage those sites and improve service. This information includes pages visits, including the date and time of the visit, the referring site (if applicable), the domain and IP address from which the access occurred, the version of browser used, the capabilities of the browser, and search terms used on our search engines. This site makes no attempt to identify individual visitors from this information: any personally identifiable information is not released to external parties without your consent unless required by law. 

**Cookies**  
Cookies are pieces of information stored by your web browser on behalf of a Web site and returned to the Web site on request. This site may use cookies for two purposes: to carry data about your current session at the site from one web page to the next and/or to identify you to the site between visits. You can change the cookie behavior of your browser in the browser preferences, choosing to accept all cookies, to accept cookies with prompting, to accept all cookies from specific websites only, or to reject all cookies. Some websites or web pages may not function properly if cookies are turned off. Unless otherwise notified on this site, we will not store data, other than for these two purposes, in cookies. Cookies remain on your computer, and accordingly we neither store cookies on our computers nor forward them to any external parties. Unless otherwise notified on this site, we do not use cookies to track your movement among different Web sites and do not exchange cookies with other entities. 

**Voluntary Information**  
In the course of using this Web site, you may opt to provide us with information to help us serve your needs, such as sending us e-mail through an application or a form to request information, opting into a mailing list, opting into our text-messaging service, or sending us your address when requesting that further information be sent to you. Any personally-identifiable information you send us will be used only for the purpose indicated. Requests for information will be directed to the appropriate staff to respond to the request, and may be recorded. We will not sell, exchange, or otherwise distribute your personally-identifiable information without your consent, except to the extent required by law. We do not retain the information longer than necessary for normal operations. Every web page requesting information discloses the purpose of that information. If you do not wish to have the information used in that manner, you are not required to provide it. Please contact the person listed on the specific page, or listed below, with questions or concerns on the use of personally-identifiable information. 

**Third-Party Sites**  
University Web sites may contain links to other web sites or web-based resources. We do not control these sites and resources, we do not endorse them, and we are not responsible for their availability, content, or delivery of services. In particular, external sites are not bound by the University's online privacy policy; they may have their own policies or none at all. Often you can tell you are leaving a University of New Haven Web site by noting the URL of the destination site. 

**University of New Haven Google Adwords and Remarketing Privacy Policy  
** University of New Haven uses all features of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers. That includes obtaining specific visitor cookie data, such as the source, medium and keyword used to visit our website. Google Analytics does not store any visitor specific data and we will not use visitor specific data in any way related to Google Analytics, Google Adwords, and Remarketing.

University of New Haven uses remarketing with Google Adwords and analytics to display content specific advertisements to visitors that have previously visited our site when those visitors go to other websites that have the Google Display Network implemented.

University of New Haven and other third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on visitor’s past visits to our website.

We take our users’ privacy very seriously. We feel that certain personal information should always be kept private, so we’ve developed restrictions around the types of ads where we don’t allow remarketing. When creating remarketing lists, we can’t use any sensitive information about users. This includes information such as their financial status, sexual orientation, and other sensitive categories.

As adwords advertisers, we are restricted from and will not perform the following actions:

(a) Running ads that collect Personally Identifiable Information (PII) including, but not limited to, email addresses, telephone numbers, and credit card numbers

(b) Creating a remarketing list or creating ad text that specifically targets users in ways that are outlined as “prohibited” in the categories below 

Visitors can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers and opt out of customized Google Display Network ads by visiting the Ads Preferences Manager in Google, or by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp "Link to Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page").

**Definitions**

  * “User” means a unique instance of a browser, application or similar technology.
  * “User Cookie” means the User identifier (of which a cookie is one example) associated with a User for remarketing or similar audiences. 
  * “Remarketing Lists” means a list of User Cookies created or otherwise obtained by you and used in connection with remarketing or similar audiences. 
  * “Similar Audiences Lists” means a list of Users created by Google based on a Remarketing List for use in connection with similar audiences. 
  * “Properties” means properties or content on which advertisements are shown.
